A Guide to the Anderson-Latham Collection, 1777-1881
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Anderson-Latham Collection, 1777-1881 (bulk 1780-1850)
Library of Virginia
23634
4.7 cubic feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Mr. Percy W. Fuller, Baltimore, Maryland, 26 December 1950.
Biographical/Historical Information
Col. Richard Clough Anderson (1750-1826) served with distinction in the Revolutionary War and, in 1783, the Governor and council of Virginia appointed him principal surveyor of the lands appropriated by Virginia for the soldiers of the Virginia line on state and continental establishments. The land was located in Kentucky and Ohio; hence Anderson established his office near Louisville. Upon his refusal to locate his office in Chillicothe he was relieved of his post as principal surveyor in 1819.
Allen Latham, a native of New Hampshire, settled in Chillicothe shortly before 1817 to practice law. In partnership with B.G. Leonard, he established an agency for soldiers' claims to land in Ohio. Latham married a daughter of Anderson and became executor of his estate, and no doubt acquired his papers.
Joseph Kerr (1765-1837) was a surveyor and land agent during the opening of the western territory. He served also as deputy surveyor of the Virginia military lands in Ohio. Kerr was very active in the business, political, and military affairs of Ohio.
Scope and Content
This collection concerns claims for military bounty land in Ohio and Kentucky which were awarded to Virginia soldiers and sailors of the Revolutionary War or to their heirs. The material is organized into the following groups: Richard C. Anderson correspondence, Allen Latham correspondence, Land Office military warrants, wills, surveys, subject files, Joseph Kerr papers, and oversized items.
Arrangement
Organized into the following eight series:
I: Richard C. Anderson Correspondence, 1780-1830
II. Allen Latham Correspondence, 1806-1856
III: Land Office Military Warrants
IV: Wills
V: Surveys
VI: Subject Files
VII: Joseph Kerr Papers, 1788-1836
VIII: Oversized Items
Contents List
- Richard C. Anderson Correspondence, 1780-1830 (Box 1-2)
  The correspondence to Richard C. Anderson and Allen Latham is largely concerned with claims for land based on Revolutionary War service, especially the disposition of those claims. There is a large amount of genealogical information contained in the letters. Many times a descendant or acquaintance is writing to Anderson or Latham inquiring about the final disposition of the claim, and they also provide details on the veteran's military service. Also contained in the letters are comments concerning speculation in these lands, as well as political matters. Notable correspondents include Duncan MacArthur, Humphrey Marshall, Peter Muhlenberg, Timothy Pickering, and Thomas Worthington.
  - 1780-1783 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1786 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1787 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1788 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1789 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1790 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1791 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1792 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1793 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1794 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1795 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1796 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1797 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1798 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1799 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1800 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1801 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1802 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1803 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1804 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1805 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1806 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1807 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1808 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1809 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1810 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1811 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1812 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1813 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1814 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1815 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1816 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1817 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1818 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1819 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1820 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1821 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1822 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1823 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1824 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1825 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1829 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 1830 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - n.d. (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Allen Latham Correspondence, 1806-1856 (Box 3-5)
  - 1806 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1816 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1817 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1818 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1819 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1820 (January-September) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1820 (October-December) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1821 (January-February) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1821 (March-June) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1821 (July-September) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1821 (October-December) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1822 (January) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1822 (February-April) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1822 (May-July) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1822 (August-September) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1822 (October-December) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1823 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1824 (January-May) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1824 (June-December) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1825 (January-June) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1825 (July-December) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1826 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1827 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1828 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 1829 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 1830 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1831 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1832 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1833 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1834 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1835 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 1836 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 1837 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 1838 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 1839 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 1840 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 1841 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 1842 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - 1843 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 1844 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 1845 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 1846 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 1847 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 1848 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - 1849 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - 1850 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - 1851 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 1852 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 1853 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 1854 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 1855 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - 1856 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - n.d. (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Land Office Military Warrants (Box 6)
  The Land Office military warrants contain information on a particular claim to land, including warrant number, veteran's name, number of acres, length of service and in what branch, and date of the warrant. Many of these warrants contain assignments, or transfers, of the land made by the veteran or their heirs to other individuals. These assignments are noted on the back of the warrant. The warrants are arranged alphabetically by veteran's surname.
  - Warrant Book (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  - Allen, Daniel (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Allen, David (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Anderson, Jordan (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Armstrong, Edward (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Arnold, Charles (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Arthur, Barnabas (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Atkinson, Reuben (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Avery, Billy H. (7) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bacon, Ludwell (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bacon, Robert (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bailey, William (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Baker, Richard (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Barton, James (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Baughan, William (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bayles, Henry (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bayles, William (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Becknall, James (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Becknall, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bell, Ning (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bennett, John (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Blackson, Pridax (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bland, James (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bond, Joseph (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bowdry, Lewis (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Boyd, James (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Boykin, Francis (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bradley, John (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Brian, William (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Briscoe, Reuben (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Brown, Edmund (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bryant, William (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Burk, Samuel (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Burnley, James (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Calfrey, Charles (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Cave, James (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Chilton, Andrew (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Conner, William (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Cooper, Hillary (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Cope, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Copin, John (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Cornelius, Josiah (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Courtney, Philip (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Coverley, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Crawford, John (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Davis, James (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Decker, Samuel (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Dickie, William (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Dillard, James (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Dodd, John (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Draper, Robert (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Drummond, James (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Dunbare, James (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Dunn, John (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Edmunds, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Elliott, Wyatt (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Emmanuel, Henry (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Farmer, Jesse (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fautz, Valentine (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Finnie, William (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fitzpatrick, Solomon (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Flournoy, Samuel (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fox, John (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fox, Nathaniel (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Gaines, William Fleming (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Galt, John Minson (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Gibbs, Harod (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Gladding, John (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Goff, Philip (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Gosset, John (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Grattan, John (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Graves, John (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Green, John (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Hall, John (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Harden, Innes (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hargis, John (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Harrison, Battaile (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hays, Daniel (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Higginbotham, William (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Holland, Drury (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hood, William (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hopkins, David (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hudson, William (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hull, Hopewell (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Humphreys, John (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hungerford, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hunt, Samuel (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hupp, Philip (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Jarvis, Francis (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Johnson, James (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Johnson, Matthew (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Johnson, Philip (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Jones, Charles (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Jones, John (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Jones, Richard (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Jordan, John (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Knight, John (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Kouts, Jacob (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Laws, John (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Lawson, Robert (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Lear, George (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Lear, John (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Lee, Philip Richard Francis (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Lewis, Andrew (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Lipscomb, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Lucas, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Maddox, Claiborne (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Martin, John (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Mayfield, Henry (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Mayfield, John (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - McCallister, John (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - McDonald, Terence (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - McDorman, David (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - McFadon, James (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Menzie, George (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Middleton, John (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Miller, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Mills, Moses (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Minor, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Moon, Archibald (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Mooney, Isaac (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Moore, Jacob (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Morris, Nathaniel G. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Moseley, William (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Moss, John (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Munford, William Green (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Muse, George (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Myers, Casper (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Neal, Charles (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - O'Neal, Ferdinand (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Owen, Richard M. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Parker, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Paul, Edward (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Payne, Daniel (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Perkins, Joseph (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Perry, William (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Pettus, John (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Philips, John (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Pool, Baxter (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Powell, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Price, Jacob (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Pullen, William (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Rains, Robert (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Ramsay, John (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Ray, Thomas (3) (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Redwood, John (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Resner, John (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Ritchie, Abraham (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Robertson, George (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Royall, William (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Rudolph, Michael (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Rumney, William (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Sailor, Martin (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Scarbrough, John (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Scott, James (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Scott, John (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Scott, John Eppes (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Sims, John (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Skinner, Alexander (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Slaughter, Philip (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Smith, Francis (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Smither, Benjamin (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Stewart, Charles (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Stewart, Robert (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Stokes, John (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Sublett, Benjamin (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Taliaferro, Nicholas (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Tannehill, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Taylor, Archibald (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Tharp, Elkanah (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Thelaball, Robert (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Thompson, John (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Tolin, Elias (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Turk, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Turner, David (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Turner, Isham (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Turner, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Turner, William (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Vandewall, Marks (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Wade, Moses (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Walker, John (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Wallace, David (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Ward, William (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Wayland, Joshua (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Welch, Patrick (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Williams, David (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Wills, Edward (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Wishart, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Wood, Benjamin (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Wood, Jesse (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Woofolk, William (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Wooten, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Wright, John (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Yager, John (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Young, George (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Young, Stephen (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Warrant Book, nos. 1 - 6730
- Wills (Box 6)
  There are a number of wills contained in this collection. Many of them are copies. A list of the testators, their residence, and date of probate can be found in the container list to the collection.
  - Andrews, William - Oglethorpe County, Georgia, 1821 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Bell, Thomas - Albemarle County, 1800 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Burgess, Dawson - Frederick County, 1799 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Campbell, Robert - Brown County, Ohio, 1831 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Gaines, Henry - King and Queen County, 1789 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Hill, Thomas - King and Queen County, 1799 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Holt, Thomas - Harrison County, Kentucky, 1822 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - McAdams, John - Northumberland County, 1784 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - McNeil, Hector - Petersburg, 1824 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Miller, William - Caroline County, 1816 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Snead, Sarah - Richmond County, 1833 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Walker, Mary - Bedford County, 1820 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - West, Anna B. - Logan County, Kentucky, 1825 (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Surveys (Box 7)
  The surveys in this collection were prepared by Anderson or Latham acting in their capacities as principal surveyors of the lands appropriated by Virginia for soldiers of the Virginia line of the State and Continental establishments. Many of these surveys were made for individuals who owned the property, not necessarily a veteran. The owner in many cases was an heir, or an individual to whom assignment had been made. The surveys are arranged alphabetically by owner's surname.
  - General Instructions to Deputy Surveyors (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Road from Foot of the Rapids of the River Miami of Lake Erie to the Western Line of the Connecticut Reserve in the State of Ohio (Field Notes) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Ayres, Francis (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Bailey, Henry (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Barton, James (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Barton, Roger (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Baughan, William (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bayles, Henry (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bayles, William (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bayles, William and Henry (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Belfield, John (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bernard, William (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bibb, Richard (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Blackson, Samuel (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Blackwell, Joseph (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Blanton, Richard (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bowles, Knight (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Boyle, Hugh (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Brown, Aaron (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Brown, John (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Brush, Henry (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Campbell, John (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Carnes, Patrick (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Casey, Peter (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cave, John (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Chambers, Joseph (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Clark, William (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cochran, Robert (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Conner, William (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cornelius, Josiah (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Crawford, John (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Culbertson, James (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Culbertson, Robert (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Dunbar, James (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Duncan, David (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Ellison, Andrew (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Farmer, Jesse (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Flecher, Henry (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Foster, Singleton (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Fox, Nathaniel's heirs (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Fulton, John A. (5) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Fulton, William (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Gatewood, Andrew (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Gholson, Ann (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Grinter, John (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Hall, John (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Harden, Innes (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Hardin, John and Gray, David (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Harness, Joseph (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Harrison, John (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Harwell, Hartwell and Mitchell, Isaac (2) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Hickman, William (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Holland, Drury (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Hulse, James (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Hulse, William (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Hunt, James (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - James, Thomas (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Jeffries, Gowin (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Johnston, William (3) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Kerr, Joseph (4) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Ladd, Joseph & Benjamin and Norvell, Thomas (6) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Landford, William (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Latham, Allen (2) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Lear, John (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Lee, Henry (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Lee, Richard heirs (3) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Lipscomb, Thomas (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Lucas, Thomas (2) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - McCormick, George (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - McDowell, John G. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - McKay, Jesse (2) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Massie, Henry (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Massie, Nathaniel (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Maupin, Gabriel (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Means, Robert (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Mires, Jacob (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Montgomery, Patrick (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Mooney, Isaac (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Moore, Robert (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Morgan, Daniel (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Moseley, William (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Moss, John and Fulton, John A. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Myers, Stephen (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Nicholas, John (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Paul, Edward (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Perry, William (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Pierce, William (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Powel, Robert (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Pursell, Alfred (3) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Ratliff, Francis (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Rawlings, Sealy (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Redwood, John (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Robertson, George (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Robinson, William (2) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Rudolph, Michael (3) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Russell, William (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Scarborough, John (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Scot, Maria Bella and William B. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Shepherd, Abraham (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Smith, Obediah (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Smith, Samuel (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Smith, Simeon (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Snead, Sarah T. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Stewart, Charles (2) (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Stokes, John (2) (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Sullivant, Lucas (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Swan, John and Taylor, James (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Tench, John (6) (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Thomas, Jesse (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Turk, Thomas (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Walke, Anthony (2) (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Wallace, David (2) (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Watkins, John (3) (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Watts, John (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Welch, Patrick (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Wilkins, William (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Williams, David (4) (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Woodson, Tarleton (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Wotton, Thomas (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Wyatt, Hubbard (2) (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Subject Files (Box 8-9)
  The subject files contain a variety of material, including accounts, affidavits, agreements, assignments, bonds, circulars, declarations, deeds, depositions, estate papers of Benjamin Hough (deputy surveyor), land entries, lists of heirs, lists of officers of the State Line and Navy, powers of attorney, receipts, and suit papers.
  - Accounts, 1778-1852 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Advice of Council re: Removal of Richard C. Anderson as Principal Surveyor, 18 February 1819 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Affidavits, 1799-1825 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Agreements (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Agreement of Deputations re: Boundaries of Lands for Soldiers of Continental and State Lines, 17 December 1783 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Appointment - Matthew Bonner, Deputy Surveyor, 1829 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Apprentice Indentures, 1795 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Articles of agreement, 1789-1821 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Articles of impeachment against Calvin Pease, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Assignments, 1784-1837 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Bonds, 1792-1823 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Circulars, 1816-1845 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Copyrights, 1806, 1814 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Declaration of Thomas Glenn, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Declaration of James Orr, 1818 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Declaration of William Stewart, 1835 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Deeds, 1802, 1819-1853 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Depositions, 1819-1832 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Discharges, 1780, 1815 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Estate Papers of Benjamin Hough, 1800-1820 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Execution, 1819 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Gregg, Daniel - Correspondence, 1858-1881 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Guardian's Appointments, 1820-1821 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Lancaster & Chilicothe Turnpike Company - Articles of Association, 1817 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Land Entries, 1784-1816 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Lists of Heirs (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Lists of Item in the Collection (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Lottery Book, 1784 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Military Pass, 1777 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Officers of the State Line and Navy (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Patents, 1830, 1841 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Potomack and Shenandoah Navigation Lottery (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Powers of attorney, 1785-1819 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Powers of attorney, 1820-1824 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Powers of attorney, 1825-1848 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Promissory note, 1819 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Protests, 1818, 1820 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Receipts (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Resolutions, 1832, 1843 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Return of Thomas Mathews' Regiment, 1781 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - A Roll of the Officers in the Virginia Line of the Revolutionary Army Who Have Received Land Bounty, in the States of Ohio and Kentucky (copy), 1822 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Sale of the Lands of Col. Francis Muir, 1819 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Stewart, Margaret - Relinquishment of Land, 1820 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Stock Certificate, 1840 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Suit Papers (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Summonses, 1820, 1826, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Tax Receipts, 1802, 1814, 1837 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Joseph Kerr Papers, 1788-1836 (Box 10)
  The Joseph Kerr Papers document his career as a farmer, politician, and deputy surveyor of Virginia military lands in Ohio. Included are accounts, agreements, Chillicothe Farm ledger, correspondence, lists of land warrants, powers of attorney, receipts, sales of cargo, suit papers, and tax receipts.
  - Accounts, 1798-1820 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Apprenticeship Indenture, 1799 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Articles of Agreement, 1796-1821 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bills of Exchange, 1815 (Box 10, Folder 4)